<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ananya Sheth</title>
    <link>https://anansheth.com/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://anansheth.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Ananya Sheth</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Ananya Sheth 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://anansheth.com/images/icon_hucdb28eb2d9bc71719683d0e0805b9e5c_26783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Ananya Sheth</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/examples/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2030 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/examples/talks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slides can be added in a few ways:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create&lt;/strong&gt; slides using Academic&amp;rsquo;s 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; feature and link using &lt;code&gt;slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upload&lt;/strong&gt; an existing slide deck to &lt;code&gt;static/&lt;/code&gt; and link using &lt;code&gt;url_slides&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the front matter of the talk file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed&lt;/strong&gt; your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further talk details can easily be added to this page using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling Up Transformational Innovations</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2024hbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2024hbr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building megaproject resilience with stakeholders: The roles of citizenship behavior and critical transition mechanisms</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2023ijpm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2023ijpm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Risk Intelligence and the Resilient Company</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2023smr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2023smr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining a typology of exploratory innovations in large-incumbent firms</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/talk/stevens-amr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/talk/stevens-amr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
--&gt;
&lt;!--Slides can be added in a few ways:

- **Create** slides using Academic&#39;s [*Slides*](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides) feature and link using `slides` parameter in the front matter of the talk file
- **Upload** an existing slide deck to `static/` and link using `url_slides` parameter in the front matter of the talk file
- **Embed** your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/).

Further talk details can easily be added to this page using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.--&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resiliency of Smart Manufacturing Enterprises via Information Integration</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2022jiii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2022jiii/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Rules for Innovation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/simple-rules-for-innovation-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/simple-rules-for-innovation-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Innovation is key to a company’s long-term success.  So, understanding the parameters of an innovation strategy is critical.  This goes beyond new technical breakthroughs, which are themselves important but not enough to ensure business success.  To achieve market success, innovative offerings require a large set of strategic choices to be made right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is well understood that not all innovation is the same.  Various prominent studies have highlighted innovation archetypes such as transformational innovations, disruptive innovations, modular innovations, enabling innovations, architectural innovations and so on.  However, these have been studied and developed as ‘special cases’ and so they explain very specific decision contexts.  This incomparable, disparate nature of innovation archetypes leads to confusion and a lack of clarity on how they can be implemented, say, to a company’s new offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0166497222000815&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;latest peer-reviewed article&lt;/a&gt; published in Elsevier’s &lt;em&gt;Technovation journal&lt;/em&gt;, we develop a simple but thorough framework that provides a common basis to cross-compare different innovation types from the lens of strategy.  The framework operates in 4 domains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt; - the vision and mission of the innovation (WHAT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope&lt;/strong&gt; - the boundaries outside which the company should not try to create an impact  (WHERE and HOW)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantage&lt;/strong&gt; - the reasons why an offering will win in the market (WHY)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flaws&lt;/strong&gt; - the likely pitfalls with an approach (WHAT NOT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each domain has decision parameters and each decision parameter has an accompanying set of questions.  Once carefully addressed, this tool would help managers by converting complex innovation strategy decisions into simple rules for strategy formulation.  The paper illustrates this implementation for 3 well known innovations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uber&lt;/strong&gt; as a &lt;em&gt;disruptive&lt;/em&gt; innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bicycle Gears&lt;/strong&gt; as a &lt;em&gt;modular&lt;/em&gt; innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fiber Optic cable&lt;/strong&gt; as an &lt;em&gt;enabling&lt;/em&gt; innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full paper can be read here: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0166497222000815&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Technovation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/Technovation-framework.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;strategy-framework&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An analytical framework to compare innovation strategies and identify simple rules</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2022tech/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2022tech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first experience teaching first-year undergrads</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/my-first-experience-teaching-first-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/my-first-experience-teaching-first-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/final_class.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;test&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctoral Dissertation Research in DRMS: Building a comprehensive understanding of enterprise risks and their interdependencies for improved risk-intelligence</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2022nsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2022nsf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer:&lt;/strong&gt; This Project Outcomes Report for the General Public is displayed verbatim as submitted by the Principle Investigator (PI) for this award. Any opinions, findings, and conclusions or recommendations expressed in this Report are those of the PI and do not necessarily reflect the views of the National Science Foundation; NSF has not approved or endorsed its content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Award Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Doctoral Dissertation Research in DRMS: Building a comprehensive understanding of enterprise risks and their interdependencies for improved risk-intelligence&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Federal Award ID:&lt;/strong&gt; 2049782&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report Submission Period:&lt;/strong&gt; 01/01/2021 to 12/31/2021&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project addressed a major gap in risk management by developing a robust inventory of the risk factors that may affect an enterprise and an understanding of the complex interdependencies between them.  This insight is foundational to build enterprise risk intelligence to foresee, and thus plan and prepare for, cascading effects caused by seemingly unrelated events.  A scientifically rigorous and data-driven approach to building risk intelligence is one of the cornerstones of creating resilient enterprises, which is critical to advancing national prosperity and welfare, thereby aligning with NSF mission. The project was carried out in 3 phases with related descriptions and outcomes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In phase 1, a comprehensive enterprise-agnostic inventory of risk factors was developed through automated information extraction from a corpus of hundreds of thousands of public and private documents describing risks to businesses of U.S. S&amp;amp;P 500 corporations.  The risk factor inventory is hosted on the Purdue University Research Repository (PURR) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://purr.purdue.edu/projects/nsfriskintelligence/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; and appended to the co-PI&amp;rsquo;s doctoral dissertation (
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.25394/PGS.15062880.v1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sheth AB, 2021&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In phase 2, the extracted risk factors were organized into a typology of enterprise risks via thematic analysis.  The outcome is an organized enterprise risk typology that can be readily queried by both researchers and practitioners alike to build awareness of risk forms and identify potentially significant risk linkages.  The typology has 5 levels, with level-5 being the broadest and containing 800+ risk factors grouped into 76 level-4 risk categories.  Risk categories belong to 18 level-3 business functions housed under 4 key business areas at level-2, which themselves are organized based on core value functions of an enterprise at level-1.  
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig-1&#34;&gt;Figure 1&lt;/a&gt; below represents the first 4 levels of the enterprise risk typology.  It is the first such typology of this scale available to the field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name =&#34;fig-1&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
| &lt;img src=&#34;figures/L1-L4-risk-network-red-center.png&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 1&#34;&gt; |
|:&amp;ndash;:|
|&lt;b&gt; Figure 1 - Enterprise risk typology levels 1 through 4 &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt; This image displays Level 1 to 4 of the enterprise risk typology developed as part of the NSF DDRIG award # 2049782. (Level 5 contains 800+ risk factors and can be found on the PURR database) |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In phase 3, the risk typology was converted into multiple complex quantified risk networks (QRNs).  Expert input was utilized to develop an understanding of inter-risk relationships.  A fully anonymous interactive survey was developed using the Qualtrics platform and circulated among academic experts and business leaders.  Knowledge of interactions between business functions (3-3) and between risk categories and business functions (4-3) was solicited from 60 experts with deep risk knowledge, operational experience, decision-making authority, or board membership in large established firms.  Responses covered 10 economic sectors and 26 industries.  A total of 18 risk networks were developed and are hosted on PURR for researchers and practitioners.  An example of inter-function interactions is shown in 
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig-2&#34;&gt;Figure 2&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name =&#34;fig-2&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
| &lt;img src=&#34;figures/L2-L2-Operating_expense_control.png&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 2&#34;&gt; |
|:&amp;ndash;:|
|&lt;b&gt; Figure 2 - Level 3-3 Risk Interactions &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Illustration of inter-function links (level 3-3). Edges represent impact between functions. Width of edges correlates to impact strength. Wider edges imply more significant relationship (with Governance), and thinner edges imply less significant relationship (with Competitive Intelligence) |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importantly, the networks highlight that some business functions such as &amp;lsquo;Governance&amp;rsquo; uniformly affect all other functions.  However, their impact may not be uniformly consequential across functions in comparison to others such as &amp;lsquo;Credit access&amp;rsquo;, which has fewer but more consequential impacts, for example, on &amp;lsquo;Financial capital management&amp;rsquo; or on &amp;lsquo;Sourcing&amp;rsquo; as shown in 
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig-3&#34;&gt;Figure 3&lt;/a&gt;.  A complete comparison is provided on the PURR repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name =&#34;fig-3&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
|&lt;img src=&#34;figures/L3-L3-functions_comparison.png&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 3&#34;&gt;|
|:&amp;ndash;:|
|&lt;b&gt; Figure 3 - Level 3-3 Inter-function interactions &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Comparison of level 3-3 interactions. Governance (left) connects uniformly to all other business functions, whereas Credit access (right) does not impact similarly. The impact of Credit access on certain functions (Product management) is stronger than that of Governance |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond inter-function relationships, expert input helped quantify the relationships between risk categories and business functions, i.e., level 4-3.  A resulting network with 75 nodes and 1044 weighted interlinks clearly indicates the complexity of enterprise risk management.  
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig-4&#34;&gt;Figure 4&lt;/a&gt; reveals that despite the large array of functions and risk categories, a smaller number are particularly high impact, as indicated by a measure of their role in connecting other risks in the network, known as &amp;lsquo;Betweenness Centrality&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name =&#34;fig-4&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
|&lt;img src=&#34;figures/L4-L3-full_network_weighted_links_with_labels.png&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 4&#34;&gt;|
|:&amp;ndash;:|
|&lt;b&gt; Figure 4 - Linkages between Level 4 risks and level 3 functions &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt; Edge width directly correlates with Edge-Betweenness such that greater width implies connection between two dense clusters. Purple links imply a high impact relationship between the risk factor and the business function, blue imply a medium impact, and yellow imply low impact |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;#fig-5&#34;&gt;Figure 5&lt;/a&gt; relates &amp;lsquo;Edge-Betweenness&amp;rsquo;, which is an indicator of the presence of dense sub-network clusters within the larger network, to the &amp;lsquo;Impact relationship&amp;rsquo; of the network, which is a quantitative measure of how much a risk category affects a function.  The figure shows edges with high &amp;lsquo;Betweenness&amp;rsquo; with both high and low impact relationships, thereby confirming the existence of dense clusters with critical links.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name =&#34;fig-5&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
|&lt;img src=&#34;figures/L4-L3-edge_betweenness-impact_relationships.png&#34; alt=&#34;Figure 5&#34;&gt;|
|:&amp;ndash;:|
|&lt;b&gt; Figure 5 - Risk Impact Evaluation (Edge-Betweenness vs. Impact)) &lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt; This figure helps to identify particularly influential QRN relationships. Points in the top right corner are characterized by high-impact relationships with high levels of Edge-Betweenness. These edges are highly central to the risk and stability of the network |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the &amp;lsquo;Product management&amp;rsquo; function and &amp;lsquo;Product regulation&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;Product liability&amp;rsquo; risk categories share edges that have high &amp;lsquo;Betweeness&amp;rsquo; implying their relevance to several other risk interrelationships.  However, and importantly, &amp;lsquo;Product liability&amp;rsquo; risks have low impact on the function overall, whereas &amp;lsquo;Product regulation&amp;rsquo; risks have a high impact.  Therefore, while both are crucial risk mitigation areas to limit negative effects from cascading across the enterprise, &amp;lsquo;regulation&amp;rsquo; warrants much more attention of practitioners and researchers seeking the goal of enterprise resiliency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The QRNs developed via this grant are resources to be further investigated to reveal insights on central and critical risks, sub-group structures in the risk network that could inform an order of risk criticality, and the cascade potential of risk events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the research conducted via this grant contributed to the field of Enterprise Risk Management (ERM) by increasing scholarly awareness on the breadth and interconnectedness of risks affecting enterprises, and by systematically converting erstwhile obscure standalone risk factors into QRNs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprises are Complex Systems</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/enterprises-are-complex-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/enterprises-are-complex-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/2021_nobel_prize_1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;test&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2021 was the first time that a Nobel Prize was awarded for “groundbreaking contributions to our understanding of complex systems”.  As a researcher studying organizations as Complex Adaptive Systems, I find this very exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the award, there has been much exposition of Complex Systems Theory.  This post briefly explains a subset class- Complex Adaptive Systems (CAS) as a contrasting viewing lens for enterprises, and its usefulness in building enterprise resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern enterprises are cyber-physical systems operating at very large scales, and although they possess management control structures such as governing boards, top-executive teams, and hierarchy for accountability, they regularly come across complexity in several forms. To comprehend the scale of operations - think of the digital products we use everyday. For example, although Google is a conventionally structured corporate organization, it relies on its base of algorithms to cater to upwards of 5 billion daily searches. In contrast, Wikipedia which gets about that many visits a month (still very high scale) is de-centralized and distinct in its organization. This de-centralized unique architecture is even more clearly witnessed in the method of operation of the open-source community. Essentially, enterprises are increasingly becoming more dependent on the cyber-physical assets, which are subject to risk.  Systems that can anticipate risk events and mitigate them prior to consequences will likely be more resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build resilience in such complex enterprises, aspiring leaders need to look beyond &amp;ldquo;resources&amp;rdquo; and at the sources of their competitive advantage, such as mechanisms to create “adaptation”. They would benefit by re-calibrating their view of enterprises from fully-controllable and governable machines to complex adaptive self-organizing systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back a hundred years to the Industrial Revolution, there have been several “theories of the firm”, which attempt to explain fundamental reasons for enterprise existence and enterprise objectives. Among them, the “evolutionary theory” has made several seminal contributions most recently. It views an enterprise as a reactor to change and creator of change for competitive advantage. The Resource Based View (RBV), which stems from the evolutionary theory, has the objective of maintaining “the stability of competitive advantage” and suggests that the competitive advantage of a firm over its competitors is constrained by the resources it possesses. Yet competitive advantage has its root in phenomena such as “innovation” and “resilience”, which are not explained by the availability and access (or lack thereof) to resources. Startups that lack resources and/or access can successfully build lasting competitive advantage. CAS provides a lens for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CASs are imagined as systems that are not particularly under the control of an “orchestrator” and instead  their behavior is governed in a hybrid manner via interactions between systems elements (at different scales)  and interactions between the external forces on the system. CAS are easily found all around us in natural systems. For instance, think of a David Attenborough documentary that films a school of fish forming beautiful structures under water. In fact, a individual fish are acting individually and collectively they are &amp;ldquo;self-organizing&amp;rdquo; to fend off larger predator fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/school_of_fish.gif&#34; alt=&#34;A school of fish in action&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, think of self-organizing flocks of starling swarms that form incredible visions in the sky while foraging and outsmart Peregrine Falcon predators with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lancswt.org.uk/blog/charlotte-varela/starling-murmuration-facts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;murmuration manoeuvres&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/starlings_flock.gif&#34; alt=&#34;A flock of starlings demonstrates complex formations in the evening sky&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with non-natural systems, imagine difficult to predict traffic patterns that have the potential to be resolved by simple non-intuitive fixes. Interestingly, science and engineering draw inspiration from these self-organizing systems and model their behavior using simple rules or heuristics at the individual (agent) level.  Humans barely act similarly and human organizations are much more complex at the agent level. Therefore, modeling them is not the right approach.  However, drawing inspiration from self-organizing systems can help us understand complex enterprise better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-imagining enterprises as CAS is not straightforward as we are conditioned to think of them as “mechanistic” structures with hierarchical chains of authority and centralized decision-making. Nowhere is this more clearly visible than in military organizations. However, it is also easy to see how this view is limiting when it comes to desirable organizational properties such as “innovation”, “resilience”, and ironically “leader-follower-ship”, which are often believed to take place “organically” within organizations.  As enterprises operate in more complex business environments, these properties become more sought after by stability-seeking organizations, the learning from the CAS analogy becomes important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pragmatic applications of this view have been developed over the past 20 years by scholars to understand the behavior of entire economies 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-50007-7_3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JH Holland 2002&lt;/a&gt;, and more recently complex supply-chains 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0272-6963%2800%2900068-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choi et. al 2001&lt;/a&gt;;  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/jbl.12270?casa_token=_M-UEm5mDvAAAAAA:KsoHjtLLMQ3BLMcGNyBzEve8OmiSgsc3pL8NIg0SMnZQQj2jw7PY2j0ZDh9KKxKSswgLPR7znOjNyHJXuQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Novak et. al 2021&lt;/a&gt;, business models 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lrp.2020.102030&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Liu et. al 2020&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ingentaconnect.com/contentone/hsp/jrmfi/2021/00000014/00000004/art00007&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;risk management&lt;/a&gt;, and leader-followership in human organizations 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2007.08521.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sheth and Sinfield 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, building enterprise resiliency needs a holistic understanding of risks, which actually are a complex network of interacting risk factors triggered by external events. An ongoing study on risk networks adopts the CAS view in building a networked view of corporate risks. This work is building a knowledge resource base, which will evetually be useful to explain mechanisms of cascading risks and to predict the varying impacts of risk events on enterprises proactively. The project is supported by the National Science Foundation (NSF) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2049782&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;award #2049782&lt;/a&gt;. It is in alignment with NSF’s mission to promote the progress of science, and via that, advance national prosperity and welfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the CAS view is perhaps the best alternative to view complex enterprises, especially as leaders begin to grapple with ever increasing complexity and seek out enterprise resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Comprehensive Typology of Complex SC Risk Networks using a Data Driven Approach</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/talk/casn-ra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/talk/casn-ra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!--&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click on the &lt;strong&gt;Slides&lt;/strong&gt; button above to view the built-in slides feature.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
--&gt;
&lt;!--Slides can be added in a few ways:

- **Create** slides using Academic&#39;s [*Slides*](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides) feature and link using `slides` parameter in the front matter of the talk file
- **Upload** an existing slide deck to `static/` and link using `url_slides` parameter in the front matter of the talk file
- **Embed** your slides (e.g. Google Slides) or presentation video on this page using [shortcodes](https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/).

Further talk details can easily be added to this page using *Markdown* and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.--&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose-Context: A framework to systematize the front-end for repeatable Innovation</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/innovation-science-purpose-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/innovation-science-purpose-contexts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/innovation_language.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;automated-tools-augment-structured-thinking-in-the-divergent-convergent-thought-process-towards-innovation-science&#34;&gt;Automated tools augment structured thinking in the divergent-convergent thought process towards Innovation Science.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation&lt;/em&gt;, a ubiquitous term in today&amp;rsquo;s world, so frequently uttered that it raises caution before use, lest one be accused of being labeled a buzz word presser. But think of it just slightly deeper and the questions pop almost instantly-  &lt;em&gt;Is innovation simply doing something differently?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Is it doing something in a particular way?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;em&gt;Does innovation simply happen?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;em&gt;Is it more frequent in a supportive ecosystem?&lt;/em&gt;  These important and significant questions have been the focus of research in the recent past, and specially so ever since we as a society have come to recognize our dependence on innovation to routinely happen for our well-being!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/Innovation/about/innoscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue University Innovation Science Lab&lt;/a&gt;, our research group has been focused on studying Innovation Science- an emergent field that attempts to investigate the innovation phenomenon such that we can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/purdue-engineering/innovation-science-theres-a-method-to-that-lightbulb-going-off-in-your-head-ce65a978422&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;move beyond chance and serendipity to process and method&lt;/a&gt;, thereby moving from &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; innovation is to &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we can innovate. We recognize the tremendous benefits of turning the innovation phenomenon into a systematic, measurable, and repeatable process, and the emerging field of Innovation Science inspires our pursuit. In that sense, the innovation process could benefit from learning by analogy. One such approach is learning from language, and this post is centered on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language is the common medium of communication between us- innovators.  Written language, sign language, even actions (think love languages) all allow us to express our thoughts and feelings, and communicate our needs and ideas. During ideation sessions and while brainstorming in groups, we&amp;rsquo;ve likely found ourselves initially lost, not knowing where to begin, then confused with several pathway possibilities, and finally struggling to make sense of a whiteboard full of ideas on a few hundred sticky notes. Yet, we see value in the ideation process as it, more often than not, serves as a nebula of innovative concepts. Importantly, it is mediated by language, and interestingly, most languages are structured constructs. Termed the grammar or syntax, the structure of language allows for it to be logically learned by large collections of agents (humans, computer programs, hybrid and multi-agent systems). In a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1108/IJIS-03-2020-0019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; recently published by our group, we attempt to learn analogously from the English language syntax for application in the front-end i.e., the problem-specification phase of the innovation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purpose-context&#34;&gt;Purpose-Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking down innovation into a simplistic act &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;develop a solution to a problem&amp;rdquo;, we quickly realize that the quality of our solutions depend wholly on the manner and clarity with which we define the problem.  In design terminology these are referred to as the problem space and the solution space. Therefore, the more specifically we define the problem space i.e.,  by adding nuanced knowledge of the world in which the problem exists, the higher is the resolution of the solution space we can generate. We think of this as the combination of a purpose (to be achieved) within a context (the constrained environment). Thus, a purpose-context pair is a problem-solution couple. Purpose-contexts are linked to the first phase of the innovation process i.e., the ideation stage. The purpose-context framing is useful because it is applicable across units of analysis for innovation. As we describe in the paper, the purpose-context framework has been applied to new product innovation, process innovation, business model innovation, technical innovation, and even in multi-stakeholder complex socio-technical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language helps us in breaking down purposes as an ACTION-PROPERTY modifier or simply a &lt;code&gt;DO-THIS&lt;/code&gt; phrase, and contexts as a LOCATION or CONSTRAINT specifier or simply &lt;code&gt;HERE&lt;/code&gt;. For example, while brainstorming for new product ideas, we may locate a market gap or an innovation opportunity in solving the problems of &amp;ldquo;unworkable shop floors.&amp;rdquo; A potential product can be thought of as being useful in &lt;code&gt;removing stickiness from a shop floor&lt;/code&gt;. Here, the purpose of &amp;ldquo;removing stickiness&amp;rdquo; is the combination of an action &lt;code&gt;TO REMOVE&lt;/code&gt; and a property &lt;code&gt;STICKINESS&lt;/code&gt;, and the context specifies the location and its constraints &lt;code&gt;A SHOP FLOOR&lt;/code&gt;. This simplistic example illustrates an important aspect of front-end innovation &amp;ndash; the breaking down of gaps, opportunities, or capabilities into nuanced word constructs that lead to substitutable and analogical connections. For instance, &amp;ldquo;sticky&amp;rdquo; can be substituted by another material property (slippery), which may require a completely different technical capability to reach a solution (and thereby a marketable product).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntactical structure enables us to programmatically derive purpose-contexts- combinatorially working bottom-up and/or working top-down via extraction from a given text. In the paper, we demonstrate both methods along with illustrations of use in real-life innovations. Mapping purposes to contexts generates purpose-context matrices, that are analyzed to form an ordered set of well-specified problem spaces, which can be grouped to recognize targeted development opportunities, make resource allocation decisions, and articulate innovation strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://anansheth.com/papers/2021_IJIS.pdf&#34;&gt;Published paper full text PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About the Author:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ananya Sheth is a Doctoral Candidate at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/Innovation/about/innoscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Innovation Science Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue University&lt;/a&gt;. Ananya is currently working on a National Science Foundation supported 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2049782&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; focused on understanding enterprise risks as complex networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Systematic problem-specification in innovation science using language</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2021ijis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2021ijis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Typology of Enterprise Risks</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/a-typology-of-enterprise-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/a-typology-of-enterprise-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Complex enterprises are vulnerable to a variety of risks.  To build an appreciation of the scale and variety of enterprise risks, I built a typology using latest data mining and data organization methods used by our group at Purdue&amp;rsquo;s Innovation Science Laboratory.  The typology uses a top level structure inspired by a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0024630120302296&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recently published paper&lt;/a&gt; from our lab.  The typology contains 700+ non-unique risks faced by enterprises, and is the base for a recent National Science Foundation award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [Have a look at the interactive risk typology here](/post/risk_typo/risk_typo.html). --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This resource is the basis for my doctoral research and in-development articles for peer-review.  Check back soon for updates on the articles, and please contact me at 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sheth7@purdue.edu&#34;&gt;sheth7@purdue.edu&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in the typology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/world_of_risk.png&#34; alt=&#34;World of Risk&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The interactive risk typology linked in this blog is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Please contact [me](mailto:sheth7@purdue.edu) to get the right citation to use the typology. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framing the Intractable -- Comprehensive Success Factor Analysis for Grand Challenges</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2020sftr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2020sftr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are university endowments using the VC vehicle adequately in their growth strategy?</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/vc-university-endowments-growth-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/vc-university-endowments-growth-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/riskgrowth.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;seeking-out-small-but-well-situated-funds-focused-on-early-stage-healthcare-tech-is-a-triple-win-for-university-endowments&#34;&gt;Seeking out small but well-situated funds focused on early-stage healthcare-tech is a triple win for university endowments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endowments exist to serve as a financial buffer, ensure the survival of an institution’s reputational capital, and protect universities’ intellectual freedom &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. To achieve these goals endowment funds are held separate from other university funds. The federal mandate for grant-funds i.e., money given away- is 5% and the remaining 95% is typically &lt;em&gt;invested&lt;/em&gt; targeting a healthy growth rate, between ~9 to 11% &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Investmentment managers take a portfolio management approach where several strategies are at play to ensure targeted growth while working under important constraints such as fiduciary responsibility to the endowment, maintaining alignment with the institutional missions, supporting university endeavours, and managing risk. A robust alternatives strategy with a focused VC component can facilitate all three objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balancing act between investment growth and risk becomes difficult under conditions of macroeconomic uncertainty such as the impact of COVID-19 or the Great Recession. At such times, strategies depending largely on stock market returns come under scrutiny &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In fact, this is the time to consider alternative investment strategies. Historically, institutional investors have preferred defensive strategies when market volatility is high such as increased investment percentage in customized hedge-funds to maintain the target growth regardless of overall market movements while keeping volatility low &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The underlying thesis is that, although hedge funds do not guarantee it, the likelihood of better performance is higher due to the star manager focus - high-touch - high-flexibility nature of the hedge fund business model. It may seem counterintuitive, but alternative investments such as early stage venture-capital are similar to hedge fund investments in certain ways. They too are idiosyncratic, domain and management team dependent, not accessible to everyone, and promise above average returns. Further, they have consistent exit timelines and thus standard investment periods, which allow them to be medium-long term investment vehicles. While long term investments in hedge funds have not proven effective &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, early stage VC promises outsized returns. These characteristics beg us to evaluate the perceived risks and search for avenues to systematically de-risk early-stage investments, especially because such investments can be highly synergistic for an endowed institution in challenging economic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This perspective seems to be shared by the large well-endowed universities. For instance, the top 20 universities with funds averaging approx. USD ~12 billion invest ~7-8% in VC and have professional investment staff responsible for identifying and constructing the investment portfolio alongside general partners. Funds averaging USD ~4 billion invest  ~5-7% and those averaging  ~$0.5 billion invest less than 5% in VC (generally via gatekeepers or funds-of-funds) &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Simply based on investment size, it becomes plausible that larger funds may receive preferential access to the most promising early stage opportunities due to the power behind their ticket size. Identifying and partnering with smaller funds who have experts focused on a specific high growth vertical (perhaps even first-time funds as they have shown greater success than established funds &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) merits serious consideration. This method is even more effective when you consider that the best performing funds have a dearth of repeat investors, making it harder for new or smaller endowments to get into these more established funds &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Furthermore, it typically takes considerable time to build up the endowment’s investment portfolio. Here is where developing a wide pipeline of potential investment opportunities and a robust evaluation system becomes crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last four decades, the world has witnessed life-changing innovations. However, and surprisingly, the distribution of innovations across sectors is not uniform, in fact it is remarkably skewed. While sectors with less regulated industries such as information technology and communications have become more accessible and cheaper, highly regulated industries such as healthcare and real estate have become less accessible and more expensive. Innovations from information technology and computing promise to reverse this trend in healthcare. Take, for instance, the promise of Artificial Intelligence- to use machine power in achieving a better human &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;. Achieving this promise has much to do with application of AI in healthcare or &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;care, if you will! The penetration of technologies such as deep vision tech in prevention, diagnosis, prognosis, and procedures is an indicator. Unsurprisingly, booming activity in the early stage VC market reflects the technological development trend. Rising healthcare costs, the industry’s patient outcomes orientation, lack of skilled professionals, new healthcare laws, and the promise of technology to solve some of the challenges creates a burning need for rapid maturity of healthcare-tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three core reasons draw attention to VC and specifically early stage VC investments in healthcare:  a). the &lt;em&gt;temporal alignment&lt;/em&gt; with the needs of the university; b). the promise of an &lt;em&gt;outsized return and buffer&lt;/em&gt; in volatile public markets; and c). The ability to &lt;em&gt;create impact&lt;/em&gt; while aligning with the university’s mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time-alignment perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
Different endowed institutions have different needs from their philanthropic investments. Hospitals (seemingly best suited investors for early stage health care) typically need returns for quicker ‘real time’ requirements such as wing upgrades and the less visible capital expansion projects such as process changes, and equipment upgrades. In contrast, universities have longer timelines that are less time-sensitive and lower capex expenditures with pre-marked allocations facilitating a more flexible investment strategy. Early stage entry in healthcare focused companies or funds becomes highly lucrative with exit opportunities over an average 7-10 year time period are likely to fetch returns ranging 2-10x multiples. Thus, being relatively less constrained by how quickly the return from an investment is sought, universities have greater leverage to thoughtfully design an early stage VC portfolio choosing from a variety of distinct-yet-related investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this happen, universities should focus on smaller but uniquely positioned funds that have a track record, strong fundamentals, legitimate participating LP’s / GP’s (subject area experts) and ideally existing investments. Doing so enables universities to be a part of opportunities (companies as well as new funds) that larger funds and larger endowments can’t invest in because they do not fit their investment size to percentage partnership ratio. University endowments placing approximately $10-15 million in staggered investments over 10 years with a promising fund and aiming to achieve a 5x return is highly lucrative and probable. An optimal ticket size in combination with exit timeframe leverage, makes early-stage healthcare a strong investment contender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The mission and impact-alignment perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
Philanthropies donate money via general (non-specific) endowments, which could result in ownership of return-generating investments that are non-aligned with the foundation’s mission. For instance, the F.B. Heron Foundation, a private foundation with a mission to help communities and people emerge out of poverty via job creation ended up owning investments in private prisons in their portfolio &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Mission-driven universities could instead invest in mission-aligned funds investing in early stage startups. Examples of mission alignment include gender focused funds (investors in female led startups), community focused funds (investors in startups in opportunity zones), and region focused funds (state specific). Investment at the early-stage provides the ability to further guide and impact the mission-venture alignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best alignment for universities whose missions undoubtedly include leading innovation come from the high enabling potential &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of AI and healthcare. Early stage investments in this domain, strategically placed, are likely to lead to technological breakthroughs that would then enable a progressive cascade of innovations improving health outcomes in any number of ways  for non-traditional populations through non-traditional delivery models &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, all enabled by the university endowment fund. A quick look at diagnostics drives home the point. Early cancer detection technologies have shown platform potential for early detection of other types of cancers (cite Interpace diagnostics). Research for technological breakthroughs has traditionally been funded through grants. Rather, investments in the space could lead to pointed and paradigm shifting impact, while delivering outsized returns because unlike grants, the commercial nature of investments leads to the team’s greater focus on producing results that can get to market and distribute a solution to the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The risk-alignment perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
Healthcare is non-seasonal, non-cyclical and early stage investments in healthcare tech are immune to losses due to market cycles, recessions, black-swans. In fact, the early-stage nature of these investments give them a strong buffer against such cyclicity because teams are focused on solution fundamentals such as validating research, performing clinical trials, obtaining reimbursement codes, and early buy-ins from physicians and not selling to a market or dependent on the market performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further de-risking is possible as universities are part of the ecosystem of the investment focus. Universities are focused on teaching and learning, positioning them aptly for innovation and commercialization by their faculty and students. This also makes them suitable as investors in areas providing preferential access to cutting-edge technology, while delivering the opportunity to monetize their own intellectual property. Universities are particularly well placed given their access to equipment, technologies and subject matter experts. Their technological focus and access to domain experts differentiate them from other investors and are all the more reason for universities to invest in early stage healthcare. The structured nature of the healthcare domain where regulatory hurdles define the runway for new technologies makes for a superior de-risked investment timeline that can be evaluated both substantively and financially. The metrics that matter in early stage healthcare like the validity of the problem, innovativeness of solution approach, scientific validation via peer-review, structured schedule of milestones, and dependence on specialists, make a university fertile ground for venture investment in early-stage healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, trends show that university endowments are growing increasingly appreciative of the opportunity provided by the venture capital vehicle.  However, there is room for a greater focus on early-stage investments in healthcare-tech and first-time funds. These investments are seemingly risky but can be de-risked as more fully discussed in a paper by my colleague M. Tellini. University endowment fund managers seek to form lasting commitments with a core group of VC funds that allow them to collectively maintain a laser sharp investment focus, thereby improving the odds of an outsized return while reducing the value-at-risk. Given the triple alignment with the university ethos, endowment funds should seek out small-but-well situated funds focused on early stage healthcare tech to score a win for not only their endowment, and not only for the millions of families that rely on it for their college scholarship, but also for the impact it has on the world in the number of lives saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About the Author:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ananya Sheth is a Doctoral Candidate at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/Innovation/about/innoscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Innovation Science Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue University&lt;/a&gt; and a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaldxventures.com/ananya-sheth.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fellow&lt;/a&gt; at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaldxventures.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DigitalDx Ventures&lt;/a&gt;, an impact fund focused on the intersection of diagnostics and artificial intelligence. Ananya has worked in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2020/Q1/two-purdue-affiliated-life-sciences-startups-receive-foundry-investment-fund-support-for-detection-technologies.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;early-stage healthcare investing at Purdue University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article first appeared on May 1st, 2020 at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaldxventures.com/are-university-endowments-using-the-vc-vehicle-adequately-in-their-growth-strategy.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DigitalDx Ventures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/d2c4/1c107b2d1916b7b4cdd09508ac02a2a936a1.pdf&#34;&gt;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/d2c4/1c107b2d1916b7b4cdd09508ac02a2a936a1.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markovprocesses.com/blog/large-and-small-endowment-performance-and-risk/&#34;&gt;https://www.markovprocesses.com/blog/large-and-small-endowment-performance-and-risk/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&#34;&gt;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/articles/03/121003.asp&#34;&gt;https://www.investopedia.com/articles/03/121003.asp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/savingandinvesting/tfsa-investors-you-can-beat-hedge-funds-with-this-dirty-little-secret/ar-AAGCg3n&#34;&gt;https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/savingandinvesting/tfsa-investors-you-can-beat-hedge-funds-with-this-dirty-little-secret/ar-AAGCg3n&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://becocapital.com/venture-capital-and-universities-a-complicated-relationship/&#34;&gt;https://becocapital.com/venture-capital-and-universities-a-complicated-relationship/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.preqin.com/reports/Preqin-Special-Report-Making-the-Case-for-First-Time-Funds-November-2016.pdf&#34;&gt;https://docs.preqin.com/reports/Preqin-Special-Report-Making-the-Case-for-First-Time-Funds-November-2016.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.venturecapitaljournal.com/investors-are-clamoring-to-get-into-homebrews-next-fund/&#34;&gt;https://www.venturecapitaljournal.com/investors-are-clamoring-to-get-into-homebrews-next-fund/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&#34;&gt;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/finding-a-lower-risk-path-to-high-impact-innovations/&#34;&gt;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/finding-a-lower-risk-path-to-high-impact-innovations/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/foundations_as_investors#&#34;&gt;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/foundations_as_investors#&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating Self-Organization during Strategic Change: Implications for Organizational Design</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/publication/2019ci/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/publication/2019ci/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Click the &lt;em&gt;Cite&lt;/em&gt; button above to demo the feature to enable visitors to import publication metadata into their reference management software.
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/slides/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/slides/example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;create-slides-in-markdown-with-academic&#34;&gt;Create slides in Markdown with Academic&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt; | 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = ;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://spectrum.chat/academic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/managing-content/#create-slides&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>News</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/news/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/news/</guid>
      <description>








&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2025&lt;/strong&gt;: Working with Cal Poly undergraduate students on a Summer Research Project is fun.. Smart kids!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2025&lt;/strong&gt;: Presented new research at the Industry Studies Association annual meet at MIT&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2025&lt;/strong&gt;: Joined the Editorial Board of Research-Technology Management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2025&lt;/strong&gt;: Offering a new course on &amp;ldquo;Entrepreneurial Strategy&amp;rdquo; at Cal Poly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: New publication alert: &lt;strong&gt;Scaling Up Transformational Innovations&lt;/strong&gt; in the Harvard Business Review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: New publication alert: &lt;strong&gt;Advancing the complex adaptive systems approach to enterprise risk management with quantified risk networks (QRNs)&lt;/strong&gt; in Nature Scientific Reports!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2024&lt;/strong&gt;: Presented papers at the Industry Studies Association annual meet and at the Academy of Management Annual meetings&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Fresh off the press: &lt;strong&gt;Risk Intelligence and the Resilient Company&lt;/strong&gt; is published as part of the MIT Sloan Management Review&amp;rsquo;s Summer 2023 issue. Great experience working with the editorial team at MITSMR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Had a highly stimulating experience at the second Management Analytics &amp;amp; Data (MAD) conference at the Columbia Business School.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Presented my paper to a great group of editors and scholars at the Academy of Management Perspectives at Fordham University&amp;rsquo;s Gabelli School of Business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Met some very interesting industry practitioners at the 2023 Front-end of Innovation conference in Boston.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Feeling excited to have submitted my first paper for review at AMR!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Attended the Journal of Management Studies Paper Development Workshop organized at Florida International University in sunny Miami. The workshop was a fantastic learning experience and an opportunity to connect with editors at JMS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Personal news: Srishti and I got married on Feb 7th at the Jersey City courthouse and in the august presence of our wonderful families. We are so so happy :D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Started teaching Introduction to Entrepreneurial Thinking to a new batch of Stevens Engineering students. Feeling excited!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;: Invited to give a research talk at the Jake Jabs School of Business and Entrepreneurship - Montana State University. Visited beautiful Bozeman :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Presented an in-preparation paper at the Stevens Business School research seminar series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Received fantastic news this morning&amp;ndash; My co-authored paper on &lt;em&gt;Risk Intelligence for Resilience&lt;/em&gt; has been provisionally accepted at &lt;em&gt;MIT-Sloan Management Review&lt;/em&gt;!  Looking forward to all the editing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Buried in sending out applications to tenure-track roles for assistant professorships :|&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Received a second round of revision request.  Phhh&amp;hellip; The good news is that the paper is improving leaps and bounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Attending AoM at Seattle in-person!  Hit me up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Put in our revision for the IJPM special issue on resilience and projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: A paper on Resiliency of Smart Manufacturing Enterprises was accepted for publication in the Journal of Industrial Information Integration! Please check out the preprint in the Publications tab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Had my final (14th) class of teaching first year undergrads! What an enjoyable and rewarding learning experience&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Wrapped up 2 NSF reports on the outcomes of our grant work! The project outcomes report can be accessed at the NSF website and  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anansheth.com/publication/2022nsf/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Paper on Innovation Strategy and Simple Rules accepted at Technovation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Paper on stakeholder citizenship behaviors and mega-project resilience accepted! at the Eastern Academy of Management conference to be held at Portland, Maine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Paper on Collective leadership in  TMT&amp;rsquo;s submitted to Organization Science!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February 2022&lt;/strong&gt;: Revision requested for our paper on mega-project resilience in the International Journal of Project Management!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Paper submitted to the Eastern Academy of Management 2022 conference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Paper on mega-project resilience submitted to the International Journal of Project Management. This is my first collaboration at Stevens!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: This has been paper revision submission month&amp;hellip; 2 sent out and 2 more to go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Our National Science Foundation project is in phase 2. In phase 1 we built a comprehensive typology of enterprise risk factors, and in phase 2 we are working with in-field experts to convert fuzzy knowledge into a quantified model. Insofar we have received inputs from 55+ industry top leaders. Phase 3 is scheduled to begin on December 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: New blog post on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.anansheth.com/post/enterprises-are-complex-systems/&#34;&gt;enterprises are complex systems&lt;/a&gt; celebrating the 2021 Nobel Prize winners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Our project on understanding high-risk Transformational Innovation projects at large companies is in full swing. This is an incredibly exciting project with high potential for insights. I am grateful to be a part of a team of top business researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Officially started as a Post-Doctoral Research Fellow at the Business School at the Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken. I am impressed by how far along this 150 year old school has come and especially the faculty at the Business School whose focus on Technology, Innovation, and Business is a perfect fit for my future goals.  Although Purdue&amp;rsquo;s shoes are tought to fill, I am sure to build a symbiotic relationship at Stevens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aug - Sept 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: The time to move from the Midwest to the East Coast&amp;hellip; A bittersweet feeling&amp;hellip; The plan is to drive through 5 states.  Keep a look out for a blog post.  I have been listening to Barack Obama&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Promised Land&amp;rdquo; and Yuval Noah Harari&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Homo Daeus&amp;rdquo;. The post will likely be influenced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 12 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Humbled by The Sinfield&amp;rsquo;s for hosting a toast and desserts evening to celebrate Dr. YuChung Lin and my graduation! The party went on late into the night &amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 11 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Had a wonderful graduation ceremony at The Elliott Hall of Music! An incredible keynote by Prof. Dr. _______ with the key takeaway that this is only the start and learning is forever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 13 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Successfully defended my doctoral thesis on &amp;ldquo;Pathways to Enterprise Resilience&amp;rdquo; where I dove deep into the two contributing sides on resilience - Comprehensive Risk Management and Systematic Growth Management!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Successfully delivered a talk on enterprise risk management at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.wpcarey.asu.edu/supply-networks/&#34;&gt;CASN-RA&lt;/a&gt; at Arizona State University. You can view the slides &lt;a href=&#34;slides/20210304-CASN-RA_Shah_Sheth.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Grateful to have been invited to present at the Complex Adaptive Suppy Networks - Research Accelerator &lt;a href=&#34;https://research.wpcarey.asu.edu/supply-networks/&#34;&gt;CASN-RA&lt;/a&gt; at Arizona State University alongwith &lt;a href=&#34;https://carlsonschool.umn.edu/faculty/rachna-shah&#34;&gt;Prof. Rachna Shah&lt;/a&gt; on March 4-5, 2021. Please see this space for event details!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Feb 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: Grateful to the Lyles School of Civil Engineering at Purdue University for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/AboutUs/News/Features/anan-sheth-receives-nsf-ddrig-award-to-study-enterprise-risks-as-complex-networks&#34;&gt;appreciation&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January 2021&lt;/strong&gt;: A co-authored article introducing parallels between the process of Innovation and Language is now published. Please access the article &lt;a href=&#34;papers/2021_IJIS.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Upcoming shortly is a demo, enabling you to rapidly extract Purpose-Context pairs from your data!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Had a successful 3rd meeting with my doctoral committee&amp;hellip; On the path to graduation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Happy to share that a proposal to the National Science Foundation was awarded! Prof. Joe Sinfield and I are co-investigators on this grant, which will help strengthen my dissertation. You can read the award &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2049782&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34;&gt;abstract here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Happy to share that a co-authored article was accepted for publication in the &amp;ldquo;International Journal of Innovation Science&amp;rdquo; by Emerald.  The article demonstrates a method to systematically pursue the front-end of the innovation process by learning analogously from the structure in Language and Natural Language Processing. The article will be up soon. Please check this space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Happy to share that a co-authored article was published in the journal &amp;ldquo;Sustainable Futures&amp;rdquo; by Elsevier.  The article introduces a general framework of success factors that are useful when framing complex socio-technical / grand challenges.&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/publication/343853213_Framing_the_Intractable_-_Comprehensive_Success_Factor_Analysis_for_Grand_Challenges&#34;&gt;Link to article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: A co-authored &lt;strong&gt;research article&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;enterprise risk complexity&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/People/view_person?resource_id=2154&#34;&gt;Dr. Joe Sinfield&lt;/a&gt; is currently in early draft stage. It views enterprise risk management from a complexity science perspective and is intended for the journal Risk Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: A co-authored &lt;strong&gt;research article&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;pathways to enterprise resilience&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/People/view_person?resource_id=2154&#34;&gt;Dr. Joe Sinfield&lt;/a&gt; is currently in late draft stage. It distills hitherto findings from my research, and is intended for executive readership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Attended the Academy of Management&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;paper development workshop on automated content analysis&lt;/strong&gt; and participated in round-table discussions with brilliant academy mentors &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.business.pitt.edu/people/lingling-pan&#34;&gt;Pan Lingling&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.ualberta.ca/directory/person/thanniga&#34;&gt;Tim Hannigan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Submitted a Doctoral Dissertation Research Improvement Grant (DDRIG) &lt;strong&gt;proposal to the National Science Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; via Purdue University with &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/People/view_person?resource_id=2154&#34;&gt;Dr. Joe Sinfield&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://polytechnic.purdue.edu/profile/taylo108&#34;&gt;Dr. Julia Rayz&lt;/a&gt; as co- senior personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&#34;publication/sftr2020&#34;&gt;Paper&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/People/view_person?resource_id=2154&#34;&gt;Dr. Joe Sinfield&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Romika_R_Kotian&#34;&gt;Romika Kotian&lt;/a&gt; was accepted for publication in Sustainable Futures - Elsevier!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Congratulations to Dr. Jucun Liu and &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/People/view_person?resource_id=2154&#34;&gt;Dr. Joe Sinfield&lt;/a&gt; of Purdue&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Innovation Science Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; for the acceptance of their  &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0024630120302296&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; on Business Models for publication in Long Range Planning!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: A co-authored &lt;strong&gt;research article&lt;/strong&gt; on the role of &lt;strong&gt;SMEs&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;International Development&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/profile/Romika_R_Kotian&#34;&gt;Romika Kotian&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/People/view_person?resource_id=2154&#34;&gt;Dr. Joe Sinfield&lt;/a&gt; is currently in analysis stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: A co-authored &lt;strong&gt;research article&lt;/strong&gt; on the systematic innovation in USA&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Marine Renewable Energy&lt;/strong&gt; sector with Abhi Ajmani and &lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/CE/People/view_person?resource_id=2154&#34;&gt;Dr. Joe Sinfield&lt;/a&gt; is currently in early draft stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Submitted three round 1 revisions in June!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2020&lt;/strong&gt;: Wrote a &lt;a href=&#34;publication/bertpriming&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; on the investment thesis of early-stage Venture Capital for University endowments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/projects/external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/projects/external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internal Project</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/projects/internal-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/projects/internal-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
