<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Ananya Sheth</title>
    <link>https://anansheth.com/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://anansheth.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Ananya Sheth 2025</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://anansheth.com/images/icon_hucdb28eb2d9bc71719683d0e0805b9e5c_26783_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Rules for Innovation Strategy</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/simple-rules-for-innovation-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/simple-rules-for-innovation-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Innovation is key to a company’s long-term success.  So, understanding the parameters of an innovation strategy is critical.  This goes beyond new technical breakthroughs, which are themselves important but not enough to ensure business success.  To achieve market success, innovative offerings require a large set of strategic choices to be made right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is well understood that not all innovation is the same.  Various prominent studies have highlighted innovation archetypes such as transformational innovations, disruptive innovations, modular innovations, enabling innovations, architectural innovations and so on.  However, these have been studied and developed as ‘special cases’ and so they explain very specific decision contexts.  This incomparable, disparate nature of innovation archetypes leads to confusion and a lack of clarity on how they can be implemented, say, to a company’s new offering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0166497222000815&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;latest peer-reviewed article&lt;/a&gt; published in Elsevier’s &lt;em&gt;Technovation journal&lt;/em&gt;, we develop a simple but thorough framework that provides a common basis to cross-compare different innovation types from the lens of strategy.  The framework operates in 4 domains:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Objective&lt;/strong&gt; - the vision and mission of the innovation (WHAT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scope&lt;/strong&gt; - the boundaries outside which the company should not try to create an impact  (WHERE and HOW)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantage&lt;/strong&gt; - the reasons why an offering will win in the market (WHY)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flaws&lt;/strong&gt; - the likely pitfalls with an approach (WHAT NOT)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each domain has decision parameters and each decision parameter has an accompanying set of questions.  Once carefully addressed, this tool would help managers by converting complex innovation strategy decisions into simple rules for strategy formulation.  The paper illustrates this implementation for 3 well known innovations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Uber&lt;/strong&gt; as a &lt;em&gt;disruptive&lt;/em&gt; innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bicycle Gears&lt;/strong&gt; as a &lt;em&gt;modular&lt;/em&gt; innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The fiber Optic cable&lt;/strong&gt; as an &lt;em&gt;enabling&lt;/em&gt; innovation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The full paper can be read here: 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0166497222000815&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Technovation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/Technovation-framework.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;strategy-framework&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first experience teaching first-year undergrads</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/my-first-experience-teaching-first-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/my-first-experience-teaching-first-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/final_class.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;test&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprises are Complex Systems</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/enterprises-are-complex-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/enterprises-are-complex-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/2021_nobel_prize_1.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;test&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2021 was the first time that a Nobel Prize was awarded for “groundbreaking contributions to our understanding of complex systems”.  As a researcher studying organizations as Complex Adaptive Systems, I find this very exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the award, there has been much exposition of Complex Systems Theory.  This post briefly explains a subset class- Complex Adaptive Systems (CAS) as a contrasting viewing lens for enterprises, and its usefulness in building enterprise resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern enterprises are cyber-physical systems operating at very large scales, and although they possess management control structures such as governing boards, top-executive teams, and hierarchy for accountability, they regularly come across complexity in several forms. To comprehend the scale of operations - think of the digital products we use everyday. For example, although Google is a conventionally structured corporate organization, it relies on its base of algorithms to cater to upwards of 5 billion daily searches. In contrast, Wikipedia which gets about that many visits a month (still very high scale) is de-centralized and distinct in its organization. This de-centralized unique architecture is even more clearly witnessed in the method of operation of the open-source community. Essentially, enterprises are increasingly becoming more dependent on the cyber-physical assets, which are subject to risk.  Systems that can anticipate risk events and mitigate them prior to consequences will likely be more resilient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To build resilience in such complex enterprises, aspiring leaders need to look beyond &amp;ldquo;resources&amp;rdquo; and at the sources of their competitive advantage, such as mechanisms to create “adaptation”. They would benefit by re-calibrating their view of enterprises from fully-controllable and governable machines to complex adaptive self-organizing systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back a hundred years to the Industrial Revolution, there have been several “theories of the firm”, which attempt to explain fundamental reasons for enterprise existence and enterprise objectives. Among them, the “evolutionary theory” has made several seminal contributions most recently. It views an enterprise as a reactor to change and creator of change for competitive advantage. The Resource Based View (RBV), which stems from the evolutionary theory, has the objective of maintaining “the stability of competitive advantage” and suggests that the competitive advantage of a firm over its competitors is constrained by the resources it possesses. Yet competitive advantage has its root in phenomena such as “innovation” and “resilience”, which are not explained by the availability and access (or lack thereof) to resources. Startups that lack resources and/or access can successfully build lasting competitive advantage. CAS provides a lens for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CASs are imagined as systems that are not particularly under the control of an “orchestrator” and instead  their behavior is governed in a hybrid manner via interactions between systems elements (at different scales)  and interactions between the external forces on the system. CAS are easily found all around us in natural systems. For instance, think of a David Attenborough documentary that films a school of fish forming beautiful structures under water. In fact, a individual fish are acting individually and collectively they are &amp;ldquo;self-organizing&amp;rdquo; to fend off larger predator fish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/school_of_fish.gif&#34; alt=&#34;A school of fish in action&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, think of self-organizing flocks of starling swarms that form incredible visions in the sky while foraging and outsmart Peregrine Falcon predators with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lancswt.org.uk/blog/charlotte-varela/starling-murmuration-facts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;murmuration manoeuvres&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/starlings_flock.gif&#34; alt=&#34;A flock of starlings demonstrates complex formations in the evening sky&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with non-natural systems, imagine difficult to predict traffic patterns that have the potential to be resolved by simple non-intuitive fixes. Interestingly, science and engineering draw inspiration from these self-organizing systems and model their behavior using simple rules or heuristics at the individual (agent) level.  Humans barely act similarly and human organizations are much more complex at the agent level. Therefore, modeling them is not the right approach.  However, drawing inspiration from self-organizing systems can help us understand complex enterprise better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Re-imagining enterprises as CAS is not straightforward as we are conditioned to think of them as “mechanistic” structures with hierarchical chains of authority and centralized decision-making. Nowhere is this more clearly visible than in military organizations. However, it is also easy to see how this view is limiting when it comes to desirable organizational properties such as “innovation”, “resilience”, and ironically “leader-follower-ship”, which are often believed to take place “organically” within organizations.  As enterprises operate in more complex business environments, these properties become more sought after by stability-seeking organizations, the learning from the CAS analogy becomes important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pragmatic applications of this view have been developed over the past 20 years by scholars to understand the behavior of entire economies 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-642-50007-7_3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;JH Holland 2002&lt;/a&gt;, and more recently complex supply-chains 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/S0272-6963%2800%2900068-1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Choi et. al 2001&lt;/a&gt;;  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/pdf/10.1111/jbl.12270?casa_token=_M-UEm5mDvAAAAAA:KsoHjtLLMQ3BLMcGNyBzEve8OmiSgsc3pL8NIg0SMnZQQj2jw7PY2j0ZDh9KKxKSswgLPR7znOjNyHJXuQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Novak et. al 2021&lt;/a&gt;, business models 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.lrp.2020.102030&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Liu et. al 2020&lt;/a&gt;, 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ingentaconnect.com/contentone/hsp/jrmfi/2021/00000014/00000004/art00007&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;risk management&lt;/a&gt;, and leader-followership in human organizations 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2007.08521.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sheth and Sinfield 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, building enterprise resiliency needs a holistic understanding of risks, which actually are a complex network of interacting risk factors triggered by external events. An ongoing study on risk networks adopts the CAS view in building a networked view of corporate risks. This work is building a knowledge resource base, which will evetually be useful to explain mechanisms of cascading risks and to predict the varying impacts of risk events on enterprises proactively. The project is supported by the National Science Foundation (NSF) 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2049782&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;award #2049782&lt;/a&gt;. It is in alignment with NSF’s mission to promote the progress of science, and via that, advance national prosperity and welfare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, the CAS view is perhaps the best alternative to view complex enterprises, especially as leaders begin to grapple with ever increasing complexity and seek out enterprise resilience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purpose-Context: A framework to systematize the front-end for repeatable Innovation</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/innovation-science-purpose-contexts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/innovation-science-purpose-contexts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/innovation_language.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;automated-tools-augment-structured-thinking-in-the-divergent-convergent-thought-process-towards-innovation-science&#34;&gt;Automated tools augment structured thinking in the divergent-convergent thought process towards Innovation Science.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Innovation&lt;/em&gt;, a ubiquitous term in today&amp;rsquo;s world, so frequently uttered that it raises caution before use, lest one be accused of being labeled a buzz word presser. But think of it just slightly deeper and the questions pop almost instantly-  &lt;em&gt;Is innovation simply doing something differently?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Is it doing something in a particular way?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;em&gt;Does innovation simply happen?&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;em&gt;Is it more frequent in a supportive ecosystem?&lt;/em&gt;  These important and significant questions have been the focus of research in the recent past, and specially so ever since we as a society have come to recognize our dependence on innovation to routinely happen for our well-being!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/Innovation/about/innoscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue University Innovation Science Lab&lt;/a&gt;, our research group has been focused on studying Innovation Science- an emergent field that attempts to investigate the innovation phenomenon such that we can 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/purdue-engineering/innovation-science-theres-a-method-to-that-lightbulb-going-off-in-your-head-ce65a978422&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;move beyond chance and serendipity to process and method&lt;/a&gt;, thereby moving from &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; innovation is to &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; we can innovate. We recognize the tremendous benefits of turning the innovation phenomenon into a systematic, measurable, and repeatable process, and the emerging field of Innovation Science inspires our pursuit. In that sense, the innovation process could benefit from learning by analogy. One such approach is learning from language, and this post is centered on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language is the common medium of communication between us- innovators.  Written language, sign language, even actions (think love languages) all allow us to express our thoughts and feelings, and communicate our needs and ideas. During ideation sessions and while brainstorming in groups, we&amp;rsquo;ve likely found ourselves initially lost, not knowing where to begin, then confused with several pathway possibilities, and finally struggling to make sense of a whiteboard full of ideas on a few hundred sticky notes. Yet, we see value in the ideation process as it, more often than not, serves as a nebula of innovative concepts. Importantly, it is mediated by language, and interestingly, most languages are structured constructs. Termed the grammar or syntax, the structure of language allows for it to be logically learned by large collections of agents (humans, computer programs, hybrid and multi-agent systems). In a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1108/IJIS-03-2020-0019&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; recently published by our group, we attempt to learn analogously from the English language syntax for application in the front-end i.e., the problem-specification phase of the innovation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;purpose-context&#34;&gt;Purpose-Context&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breaking down innovation into a simplistic act &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;develop a solution to a problem&amp;rdquo;, we quickly realize that the quality of our solutions depend wholly on the manner and clarity with which we define the problem.  In design terminology these are referred to as the problem space and the solution space. Therefore, the more specifically we define the problem space i.e.,  by adding nuanced knowledge of the world in which the problem exists, the higher is the resolution of the solution space we can generate. We think of this as the combination of a purpose (to be achieved) within a context (the constrained environment). Thus, a purpose-context pair is a problem-solution couple. Purpose-contexts are linked to the first phase of the innovation process i.e., the ideation stage. The purpose-context framing is useful because it is applicable across units of analysis for innovation. As we describe in the paper, the purpose-context framework has been applied to new product innovation, process innovation, business model innovation, technical innovation, and even in multi-stakeholder complex socio-technical challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Language helps us in breaking down purposes as an ACTION-PROPERTY modifier or simply a &lt;code&gt;DO-THIS&lt;/code&gt; phrase, and contexts as a LOCATION or CONSTRAINT specifier or simply &lt;code&gt;HERE&lt;/code&gt;. For example, while brainstorming for new product ideas, we may locate a market gap or an innovation opportunity in solving the problems of &amp;ldquo;unworkable shop floors.&amp;rdquo; A potential product can be thought of as being useful in &lt;code&gt;removing stickiness from a shop floor&lt;/code&gt;. Here, the purpose of &amp;ldquo;removing stickiness&amp;rdquo; is the combination of an action &lt;code&gt;TO REMOVE&lt;/code&gt; and a property &lt;code&gt;STICKINESS&lt;/code&gt;, and the context specifies the location and its constraints &lt;code&gt;A SHOP FLOOR&lt;/code&gt;. This simplistic example illustrates an important aspect of front-end innovation &amp;ndash; the breaking down of gaps, opportunities, or capabilities into nuanced word constructs that lead to substitutable and analogical connections. For instance, &amp;ldquo;sticky&amp;rdquo; can be substituted by another material property (slippery), which may require a completely different technical capability to reach a solution (and thereby a marketable product).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syntactical structure enables us to programmatically derive purpose-contexts- combinatorially working bottom-up and/or working top-down via extraction from a given text. In the paper, we demonstrate both methods along with illustrations of use in real-life innovations. Mapping purposes to contexts generates purpose-context matrices, that are analyzed to form an ordered set of well-specified problem spaces, which can be grouped to recognize targeted development opportunities, make resource allocation decisions, and articulate innovation strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://anansheth.com/papers/2021_IJIS.pdf&#34;&gt;Published paper full text PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About the Author:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ananya Sheth is a Doctoral Candidate at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/Innovation/about/innoscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Innovation Science Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue University&lt;/a&gt;. Ananya is currently working on a National Science Foundation supported 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsf.gov/awardsearch/showAward?AWD_ID=2049782&amp;amp;HistoricalAwards=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;project&lt;/a&gt; focused on understanding enterprise risks as complex networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Typology of Enterprise Risks</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/a-typology-of-enterprise-risks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/a-typology-of-enterprise-risks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Complex enterprises are vulnerable to a variety of risks.  To build an appreciation of the scale and variety of enterprise risks, I built a typology using latest data mining and data organization methods used by our group at Purdue&amp;rsquo;s Innovation Science Laboratory.  The typology uses a top level structure inspired by a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0024630120302296&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;recently published paper&lt;/a&gt; from our lab.  The typology contains 700+ non-unique risks faced by enterprises, and is the base for a recent National Science Foundation award.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- [Have a look at the interactive risk typology here](/post/risk_typo/risk_typo.html). --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This resource is the basis for my doctoral research and in-development articles for peer-review.  Check back soon for updates on the articles, and please contact me at 
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:sheth7@purdue.edu&#34;&gt;sheth7@purdue.edu&lt;/a&gt; if you are interested in the typology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/world_of_risk.png&#34; alt=&#34;World of Risk&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Creative Commons License&#34; style=&#34;border-width:0&#34; src=&#34;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by/4.0/88x31.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The interactive risk typology linked in this blog is licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#34;license&#34; href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- Please contact [me](mailto:sheth7@purdue.edu) to get the right citation to use the typology. --&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are university endowments using the VC vehicle adequately in their growth strategy?</title>
      <link>https://anansheth.com/post/vc-university-endowments-growth-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://anansheth.com/post/vc-university-endowments-growth-strategy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://anansheth.com/img/riskgrowth.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;seeking-out-small-but-well-situated-funds-focused-on-early-stage-healthcare-tech-is-a-triple-win-for-university-endowments&#34;&gt;Seeking out small but well-situated funds focused on early-stage healthcare-tech is a triple win for university endowments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Endowments exist to serve as a financial buffer, ensure the survival of an institution’s reputational capital, and protect universities’ intellectual freedom &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. To achieve these goals endowment funds are held separate from other university funds. The federal mandate for grant-funds i.e., money given away- is 5% and the remaining 95% is typically &lt;em&gt;invested&lt;/em&gt; targeting a healthy growth rate, between ~9 to 11% &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Investmentment managers take a portfolio management approach where several strategies are at play to ensure targeted growth while working under important constraints such as fiduciary responsibility to the endowment, maintaining alignment with the institutional missions, supporting university endeavours, and managing risk. A robust alternatives strategy with a focused VC component can facilitate all three objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The balancing act between investment growth and risk becomes difficult under conditions of macroeconomic uncertainty such as the impact of COVID-19 or the Great Recession. At such times, strategies depending largely on stock market returns come under scrutiny &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In fact, this is the time to consider alternative investment strategies. Historically, institutional investors have preferred defensive strategies when market volatility is high such as increased investment percentage in customized hedge-funds to maintain the target growth regardless of overall market movements while keeping volatility low &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The underlying thesis is that, although hedge funds do not guarantee it, the likelihood of better performance is higher due to the star manager focus - high-touch - high-flexibility nature of the hedge fund business model. It may seem counterintuitive, but alternative investments such as early stage venture-capital are similar to hedge fund investments in certain ways. They too are idiosyncratic, domain and management team dependent, not accessible to everyone, and promise above average returns. Further, they have consistent exit timelines and thus standard investment periods, which allow them to be medium-long term investment vehicles. While long term investments in hedge funds have not proven effective &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, early stage VC promises outsized returns. These characteristics beg us to evaluate the perceived risks and search for avenues to systematically de-risk early-stage investments, especially because such investments can be highly synergistic for an endowed institution in challenging economic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This perspective seems to be shared by the large well-endowed universities. For instance, the top 20 universities with funds averaging approx. USD ~12 billion invest ~7-8% in VC and have professional investment staff responsible for identifying and constructing the investment portfolio alongside general partners. Funds averaging USD ~4 billion invest  ~5-7% and those averaging  ~$0.5 billion invest less than 5% in VC (generally via gatekeepers or funds-of-funds) &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Simply based on investment size, it becomes plausible that larger funds may receive preferential access to the most promising early stage opportunities due to the power behind their ticket size. Identifying and partnering with smaller funds who have experts focused on a specific high growth vertical (perhaps even first-time funds as they have shown greater success than established funds &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;) merits serious consideration. This method is even more effective when you consider that the best performing funds have a dearth of repeat investors, making it harder for new or smaller endowments to get into these more established funds &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Furthermore, it typically takes considerable time to build up the endowment’s investment portfolio. Here is where developing a wide pipeline of potential investment opportunities and a robust evaluation system becomes crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last four decades, the world has witnessed life-changing innovations. However, and surprisingly, the distribution of innovations across sectors is not uniform, in fact it is remarkably skewed. While sectors with less regulated industries such as information technology and communications have become more accessible and cheaper, highly regulated industries such as healthcare and real estate have become less accessible and more expensive. Innovations from information technology and computing promise to reverse this trend in healthcare. Take, for instance, the promise of Artificial Intelligence- to use machine power in achieving a better human &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;. Achieving this promise has much to do with application of AI in healthcare or &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt;care, if you will! The penetration of technologies such as deep vision tech in prevention, diagnosis, prognosis, and procedures is an indicator. Unsurprisingly, booming activity in the early stage VC market reflects the technological development trend. Rising healthcare costs, the industry’s patient outcomes orientation, lack of skilled professionals, new healthcare laws, and the promise of technology to solve some of the challenges creates a burning need for rapid maturity of healthcare-tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three core reasons draw attention to VC and specifically early stage VC investments in healthcare:  a). the &lt;em&gt;temporal alignment&lt;/em&gt; with the needs of the university; b). the promise of an &lt;em&gt;outsized return and buffer&lt;/em&gt; in volatile public markets; and c). The ability to &lt;em&gt;create impact&lt;/em&gt; while aligning with the university’s mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time-alignment perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
Different endowed institutions have different needs from their philanthropic investments. Hospitals (seemingly best suited investors for early stage health care) typically need returns for quicker ‘real time’ requirements such as wing upgrades and the less visible capital expansion projects such as process changes, and equipment upgrades. In contrast, universities have longer timelines that are less time-sensitive and lower capex expenditures with pre-marked allocations facilitating a more flexible investment strategy. Early stage entry in healthcare focused companies or funds becomes highly lucrative with exit opportunities over an average 7-10 year time period are likely to fetch returns ranging 2-10x multiples. Thus, being relatively less constrained by how quickly the return from an investment is sought, universities have greater leverage to thoughtfully design an early stage VC portfolio choosing from a variety of distinct-yet-related investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make this happen, universities should focus on smaller but uniquely positioned funds that have a track record, strong fundamentals, legitimate participating LP’s / GP’s (subject area experts) and ideally existing investments. Doing so enables universities to be a part of opportunities (companies as well as new funds) that larger funds and larger endowments can’t invest in because they do not fit their investment size to percentage partnership ratio. University endowments placing approximately $10-15 million in staggered investments over 10 years with a promising fund and aiming to achieve a 5x return is highly lucrative and probable. An optimal ticket size in combination with exit timeframe leverage, makes early-stage healthcare a strong investment contender.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The mission and impact-alignment perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
Philanthropies donate money via general (non-specific) endowments, which could result in ownership of return-generating investments that are non-aligned with the foundation’s mission. For instance, the F.B. Heron Foundation, a private foundation with a mission to help communities and people emerge out of poverty via job creation ended up owning investments in private prisons in their portfolio &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Mission-driven universities could instead invest in mission-aligned funds investing in early stage startups. Examples of mission alignment include gender focused funds (investors in female led startups), community focused funds (investors in startups in opportunity zones), and region focused funds (state specific). Investment at the early-stage provides the ability to further guide and impact the mission-venture alignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best alignment for universities whose missions undoubtedly include leading innovation come from the high enabling potential &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:10&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; of AI and healthcare. Early stage investments in this domain, strategically placed, are likely to lead to technological breakthroughs that would then enable a progressive cascade of innovations improving health outcomes in any number of ways  for non-traditional populations through non-traditional delivery models &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:11&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, all enabled by the university endowment fund. A quick look at diagnostics drives home the point. Early cancer detection technologies have shown platform potential for early detection of other types of cancers (cite Interpace diagnostics). Research for technological breakthroughs has traditionally been funded through grants. Rather, investments in the space could lead to pointed and paradigm shifting impact, while delivering outsized returns because unlike grants, the commercial nature of investments leads to the team’s greater focus on producing results that can get to market and distribute a solution to the population.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The risk-alignment perspective:&lt;/strong&gt;
Healthcare is non-seasonal, non-cyclical and early stage investments in healthcare tech are immune to losses due to market cycles, recessions, black-swans. In fact, the early-stage nature of these investments give them a strong buffer against such cyclicity because teams are focused on solution fundamentals such as validating research, performing clinical trials, obtaining reimbursement codes, and early buy-ins from physicians and not selling to a market or dependent on the market performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further de-risking is possible as universities are part of the ecosystem of the investment focus. Universities are focused on teaching and learning, positioning them aptly for innovation and commercialization by their faculty and students. This also makes them suitable as investors in areas providing preferential access to cutting-edge technology, while delivering the opportunity to monetize their own intellectual property. Universities are particularly well placed given their access to equipment, technologies and subject matter experts. Their technological focus and access to domain experts differentiate them from other investors and are all the more reason for universities to invest in early stage healthcare. The structured nature of the healthcare domain where regulatory hurdles define the runway for new technologies makes for a superior de-risked investment timeline that can be evaluated both substantively and financially. The metrics that matter in early stage healthcare like the validity of the problem, innovativeness of solution approach, scientific validation via peer-review, structured schedule of milestones, and dependence on specialists, make a university fertile ground for venture investment in early-stage healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In closing, trends show that university endowments are growing increasingly appreciative of the opportunity provided by the venture capital vehicle.  However, there is room for a greater focus on early-stage investments in healthcare-tech and first-time funds. These investments are seemingly risky but can be de-risked as more fully discussed in a paper by my colleague M. Tellini. University endowment fund managers seek to form lasting commitments with a core group of VC funds that allow them to collectively maintain a laser sharp investment focus, thereby improving the odds of an outsized return while reducing the value-at-risk. Given the triple alignment with the university ethos, endowment funds should seek out small-but-well situated funds focused on early stage healthcare tech to score a win for not only their endowment, and not only for the millions of families that rely on it for their college scholarship, but also for the impact it has on the world in the number of lives saved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;About the Author:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ananya Sheth is a Doctoral Candidate at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://engineering.purdue.edu/Innovation/about/innoscience&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Innovation Science Laboratory&lt;/a&gt; of 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Purdue University&lt;/a&gt; and a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaldxventures.com/ananya-sheth.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fellow&lt;/a&gt; at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaldxventures.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DigitalDx Ventures&lt;/a&gt;, an impact fund focused on the intersection of diagnostics and artificial intelligence. Ananya has worked in 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.purdue.edu/newsroom/releases/2020/Q1/two-purdue-affiliated-life-sciences-startups-receive-foundry-investment-fund-support-for-detection-technologies.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;early-stage healthcare investing at Purdue University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article first appeared on May 1st, 2020 at 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitaldxventures.com/are-university-endowments-using-the-vc-vehicle-adequately-in-their-growth-strategy.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;DigitalDx Ventures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;section class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/d2c4/1c107b2d1916b7b4cdd09508ac02a2a936a1.pdf&#34;&gt;https://pdfs.semanticscholar.org/d2c4/1c107b2d1916b7b4cdd09508ac02a2a936a1.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.markovprocesses.com/blog/large-and-small-endowment-performance-and-risk/&#34;&gt;https://www.markovprocesses.com/blog/large-and-small-endowment-performance-and-risk/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&#34;&gt;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/articles/03/121003.asp&#34;&gt;https://www.investopedia.com/articles/03/121003.asp&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/savingandinvesting/tfsa-investors-you-can-beat-hedge-funds-with-this-dirty-little-secret/ar-AAGCg3n&#34;&gt;https://www.msn.com/en-us/money/savingandinvesting/tfsa-investors-you-can-beat-hedge-funds-with-this-dirty-little-secret/ar-AAGCg3n&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://becocapital.com/venture-capital-and-universities-a-complicated-relationship/&#34;&gt;https://becocapital.com/venture-capital-and-universities-a-complicated-relationship/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.preqin.com/reports/Preqin-Special-Report-Making-the-Case-for-First-Time-Funds-November-2016.pdf&#34;&gt;https://docs.preqin.com/reports/Preqin-Special-Report-Making-the-Case-for-First-Time-Funds-November-2016.pdf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.venturecapitaljournal.com/investors-are-clamoring-to-get-into-homebrews-next-fund/&#34;&gt;https://www.venturecapitaljournal.com/investors-are-clamoring-to-get-into-homebrews-next-fund/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&#34;&gt;https://www.yesmagazine.org/issue/good-money/2018/11/27/your-favorite-charity-has-most-of-its-money-in-wall-street/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:10&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/finding-a-lower-risk-path-to-high-impact-innovations/&#34;&gt;https://sloanreview.mit.edu/article/finding-a-lower-risk-path-to-high-impact-innovations/&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:10&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:11&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnote&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/foundations_as_investors#&#34;&gt;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/foundations_as_investors#&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:11&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
